# Sean Coughlin

Associate Software Engineer

# Profile

I am a motivated Associate Software Engineer pursuing a Master of Computer Science with 1+ years of experience. As a dedicated full-stack engineer, I display expert Java, JavaScript, and React development skills while supporting applications used by millions of customers every month.

# **Employment History**

# **Associate Software Engineer at Discover Financial Services**

Riverwoods, IL, February 2022 — Present

- Drove the development of a new multi-factor authentication credit card application process, reducing required user inputs by 50%
- Implemented a new caching process increasing customer security for 600,000 customers a month
- Delivered standardized React components, shortening project delivery dates by one month
- Improved static content deployment processes, decreasing installation errors from 30% to 0%
- Advanced a weekly release cadence for eight microservices and resolved production errors while on call

### **Software Engineering Intern at Discover Financial Services**

Riverwoods, IL, June 2021 — August 2021

- Engineered a comprehensive API testing, documentation, and demonstration tool for product owners using Angular, Spring Boot, and Swagger
- Delivered code across the digital payments ecosystem that resolved 50 code quality issues and updated APIs to support new software versions
- Furthered Scrum and Kanban based Agile teams by formulating user stories aligning to behavior driven development and fulfilling business requirements

## **Quality Assurance Intern at Zebra Technologies**

Lincolnshire, IL, May 2020 — August 2020

- Generated a 57% reduction in testing time through expanding automated functional tests and accelerated the IT department's Agile transformation
- Streamlined the IT quality assurance team's on boarding process by building comprehensive documentation explaining team tools and best practices

## Education

# Master of Computer Science, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

August 2022 — May 2024

- GPA: 3.83 / 4.00
- Select Coursework: Cloud Computing Applications, Cloud Networking, Software Engineering

# Bachelor of Science Computer Science, Economics Minor, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

August 2018 — December 2021

- GPA: 3.88 / 4.00, High Honors
- Designed outreach programs on behalf of the University of Illinois for elementary and middle schools to encourage youth interest in STEM fields and excite future generations of engineers

#### **Details**

Chicago, IL

847-226-9006

coughlinscc33@gmail.com

LinkedIn

**GitHub** 

seancoughlin.me

#### **Skills**

Java

**Spring Boot** 

JavaScript (NodeJS, jQuery)

React

HTML/CSS

Git

SQL (MySQL, NoSQL)

Jira

PCF

CI/CD (Jenkins)

Cucumber

### **Personal Projects**

### **Software Engineering Blog**

Maintaining a software engineering writing series currently with 26 articles and 10,000+ views

### **Compound Interest Solver**

Created an iOS app for financial calculations that has been downloaded over 250 times

## **Swimming Stroke Detector**

Built an object detector using Tensorflow and constructed a custom dataset for recognizing the four swimming strokes

### **Hobbies**

Mountain climbing, hiking, running, weight lifting